<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>datascience - Tag - Evolving notes on crafting a good life</title>
        <link>http://example.org/tags/datascience/</link>
        <description>datascience - Tag - Evolving notes on crafting a good life</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/datascience/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Machine learning basics</title>
    <link>http://example.org/machine-learning-basics/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/machine-learning-basics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction and definitions Why do we estimate f?
Purpose of ml is often to infer a function f that describes the relationship between target and features.
Can estimate f for (1) prediction or (2) inference or both.
How do we estimate f?
3 basic approaches: parametric (assume shape of f and estimate coefficients), non-parametric (also estimate shape of f), semi-parametric.
Accuracy depends on (1) irreducible error (variance of error term) and (2) reducible error (appropriateness of our model and its assumptions)]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Seattle bicycle traffic</title>
    <link>http://example.org/seattle-bicycle-traffic/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/seattle-bicycle-traffic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This notebook contains my replication of this blog post by Jake VanderPlas on using data from bicycle traffic across Seattle&rsquo;s Fremont Bridge to learn about commuting patterns.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 import os import ssl from urllib.request import urlretrieve import altair as alt import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np import pandas as pd import seaborn from pandas.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Waiting time paradox</title>
    <link>http://example.org/waiting-time-paradox/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/waiting-time-paradox/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This notebook replicates Jake VanderPlas&rsquo; awesome post on the topic.
Background The waiting-time paradox is a special case of the inspection paradox, which &ndash; as VanderPlas succinctly summarises &ndash; occurs whenever the probability of observing a quantity is related to the quantity being observed. For example: if you sample random students on campus and ask them about the size of their classes you&rsquo;ll probably get a larger number than if you asked the collge administrator, because you&rsquo;re likely to oversample students from large classes.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Naive Bayes</title>
    <link>http://example.org/naive-bayes/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/naive-bayes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[## Setup
We&rsquo;re interested in estimating $P(L|features)$, the probability of a label given a collection of features.
Bayes&rsquo;s formula helps us express this in terms of things we can measure in the data as:
$$P(L|features) = \frac{P(features|L) * P(L)}{P(features)}$$
To decide which label is more probable given a set of features, we can compute the posterior ratio of likelihoods:
$$\frac{P(L_1|features)}{P(L_2|features)} = \frac{P(features|L_1) * P(L_1)}{P(features|L_2) * P(L_2)}$$.
To be able to do this, we need to specify a generative model (a hypothetical random process that generates the data) for each label in the data.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
